The letters T and D occur frequently throughout the Tamil texts in the accompanying book.
It is important not to pronounce these in the same way as English T and D.
Used for Tamil, these letters represent dental sounds, as in French.
When you articulate them, make sure that the tip of your tongue touches the upper front teeth.
Careful listening will show that D has a different pronunciation depending on what other sounds come next to it.
At the beginning of a word, and after N in the middle of a word, it has a sound very close to that of a French D, as just mentioned.
When it occurs between vowels in the middle of a word, however, it sounds more like the "th" in English "other".
Listen carefully to these features of the following words, and then repeat them.
Street
தெரு (teru)
How many
எத்தனை (ettane)
Daily
தினம் (dinam)
That
அந்த (anda)
It
அது (adu)